The Final Battle
The Earth will be used to generate an endless supply of core metal.
And I will save our people of steel... from the threat of extinction!
Is that your goal?
Yes. It is my dream to reconstruct planet Machina!
And you don't care... that the people and creatures of this planet have to disappear for that dream?!
It's a small sacrifice I'm willing to make for a bigger goal.
A small sacrifice?!
Hm?
We're all doing our best just to live our lives!
No one has the right to take that away!
Jun!
I... will never give up!!
Humans...
Metal Cardbots!
I will protect them all!
It's happening again...
Jun! Unleash the forbidden power!
That is the only way to defeat him!
Wait!
The power sealed within the Metal Breath could be dangerous for him!
-Haha! What are you saying?
-Jun!
We've faced countless dangers together, and overcame every last one!
So long as we're together, there's nothing we can't do!
Okay.
We haven't given up either!
Guys!
We still got an ace up our sleeve.
Don't count us out!
We're always together!
Yes. The real battle begins now!
We show warmth of your heart-
-to that big oaf over there!
Jun, Blue Cop. Let's combine our strength!
Oh... look at that!
Jun's spirit and determination to never give up has combined with the spirit of the Metal Cardbots... to awaken... the forbidden power!
Our hearts gathered...
...as one!
Ultimate Armor... setup! (FX-ua)
All the power of planet Machina...
is coursing through our veins.
Jun, are you alright?
Mhm!
Get ready! Everyone!
Edge Acceleration!
You'll have to try harder than that!
Mega Power Shield! (FX-megaTrucker shake bold)
Spear Thrust! (FX-dexter shake bold)
Captain's Cannon! (FX-blackHook shake bold)
Keep up the pressure!
Wild Raid! (FX-wildGuardy shake bold)
Not bad!
Twin Vulcan! (FX-busterGallon shake bold)
Spinning Cutter! (FX-shadowX shake bold)
Forceps Crush! (FX-megaAmbler shake bold)
Buffalo Moonsault! (FX-buffaloCrush shake bold)
Hammer Blaze! (FX-phoenixFire shake bold)
Vulture Wings! (FX-fletaZ shake bold)
You think this is enough to defeat me?
We're not finished yet!
Lightning... (FX-shake bold)
Over... (FX-shakexl bold)
Strike!! (FX-shakexxl bold ua)
How dare you...
Incredible! So this is the forbidden powe-
A-aagh! (FX-shake phoenixFire)
Jun! Are you okay?!
I'm okay!
Aah! Blue Cop!
Agh!
What is it, Jun?!
The Metal Breath! It's starting to burn!
What?!
Is the forbidden power going out of control?! Take off the Metal Breath, now!
No! We keep fighting!
Please, Jun!
I won't take it off!
Not until he's sealed!
But...
If we stop now, everything we've done would have all been for nothing!
The day you and I met!
The friends we made along the way!
So you should know by now...
That I will never give up!
For a world where humans and Metal Cardbots can live together!
I will never give up on that dream!
Such a world...
Will never exist!!
For this planet to become our new home...
You humans cannot survive!
No!
I know we can exist alongside humans.
They've been kind and compassionate enough... to accept us Metal Cardbots!
Silence!!
Infinite... (FX-ua shake)
Punish!! (FX-ua shakexxl)
Jun!
Hey, guys!
Don't get any closer, please!
Ugh... the Star Crown is still alive...
As long as I have it... my dream will...
Huh...?!
Blue Cop!
Setup!
Seems like... you still haven't learned your lesson.
Heh. Looks like you didn't hear me.
I will never give up!
Infinity...
Force...
Megabolt... (FX-shake)
Punch!! (FX-shakexl blueCop)
Iron Cannon!!
Metal Cardbot...
Change Up!
My dream... was to revive my home planet.
Why do you get in my way?...
Because it's my dream to live together with my friends!
I just wanted to protect my dream too!
I see...
I concede.
Heavy Iron...
Sealed!
Nooo!!
What happened to Jun?! And everyone else?!
I should have stopped him... Even if I had to drag him out of there.
What the heck happened to Jun?
Jun!!
I can't believe he's been...
What's wrong, guys?
Well, you see... the thing is-
What?! Jun?!
You're alright?!
All thanks to my good friends!
Blue Cop!
Oh you little- I was so worried about you!
I thought you got crushed out there!
I'm sorry... Here.
But hey! I'm back safe and sound.
Thank you...
Here you go.
Eugh.
I'm so glad you're okay!
Welcome back, Jun!
What's gotten into them?
It seems like a brave police officer managed to go inside and rescue the boy.
Please, can I have an interview?
That evening...
we were given a huge scolding.
Huh?
Jun?
Mom... I can explain...
It didn't hurt that much, Mom!
I'm sure the scar will be gone in a week!
Listen to me!
I'll never forgive you if you put yourself in danger like that again!
And I won't let you play with your friends ever again!
What?!- Ah.. That hurt.
Isn't that a bit much?
Yuri! Please forgive Jun!
Quiet!
...okay...
I'm really sorry.
I know you just wanted to help your friends.
But do you know how worried I was?
I won't do it again, Mom...
We also took care of the aftermath in secret.
According to Buster Gallon, most of the Machinasium turned into ordinary rock when the Star Crown was destroyed.
However, it seems like a few scattered pieces are still alive.
Ugh. This is gonna take forever.
Hey! Let's bet on who can find the most!
Me sure to win!
No way!
Vera, who saw what happened that day, seems to believe that the dome was the base for an alien invasion.
Well... she's kinda right!
Ha! I heard it on TV!
A bunch of underground elements had a chemical reaction with the methane gas and puffed up like bread!
Vance, you're the smartest!
Don't be fooled! They-
See you later, Vera!
We'll be off then!
Jun! You saw it, didn't you?
Aliens?
I'm sure they exist! Space is huge, right?
According to the Drake equation, there are 25,000 planets in this galaxy likely to have alien civilizations!
Jun! We have a situation!
Huh?! I know that voice!
Uh, see ya!
Hey, wait!
And now... we're doing a routine cleaning of the warehouse together!
Since we have some new big friends joining us, we have to get on Uncle Edo's good side!
Although... the big guy doesn't seem to have opened up yet.
This stain just won't come out.
Disappointing, Blue Cop. I'll show you how it's done!
Why the long face over there?!
This is just pathetic to watch.
I can't believe you're all playing along.
This is how we clean up on Earth. Why not give it a try?
Do you really think I'd do something so pitiful?
Haha! What, afraid you can't do it?
What was that?
Yeah! Can ya? Can ya?
Hm. I don't think he can.
What a persistent stain-
Move it!
I'll show you that I'm on a different level than those who would surrender to humans.
You can't solve everything just by using force.
Here, try spraying some of-
Woah, woah!
Heh! Fire makes for the best cleaning agent!
-Hahaha!
-Phoenix Fire! Red alert!
Huh?!
-Oh no, danger!
-Hey, you troublemakers! What do you think you're doing?!
Dousing the fire!
Uh...
Jun! I think we have an emergency!
Everyone, run for it!!
You won't keep getting away with this!!
Phew! So we had to run all the way out here...
Yeah... and to think I ran away with you.
Isn't that proof that you've become one of our friends?
Look at the sky, Heavy Iron!
Hmm?
Planet Machina doesn't exist anymore.
So now you have to live here on Earth with us!
Jun?
What point is there in trying to open up emotional wounds?
But...
Huh?
We don't know how many Metal Cardbots are still drifting through the universe...
Lost somewhere among the stars.
Let's make it our role to give them a warm welcome when they arrive here on Earth!
So let's work together, and create a world where humans and Metal Cardbots can coexist and be friends, Heavy Iron!
I think... I'm starting to understand you.
Let's work together. For the future of Metal Cardbots.
Thank you, Heavy Iron!
This is great!
So we've made yet another incredible friend.
Now can you give it a rest with the eyes?
Hmph.
Woah! Now you look more reasonable!
Right?!
Deus Machina...
Was this the reason...
That you chose him?